<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
<jobs>
    <job>
        <title>Full Stack Engineer - Remote from EMEA</title>
        <id>4192882101</id>
        <![CDATA[<description>
        Wakam is a European B2B2C insurer that designs white label insurance products for its partners (e-retailers, brokers and fintechs/insurtechs, etc.).
​
        Our insurance products have the particularity of being embedded in the products or services offered to the end-customer (for example, you take a self-service e-scooter, you are automatically insured). Wakam operates in 32 European countries with the majority of its turnover generated outside France.
​
        The company provides most of its products through API, and hosts white label insurance solutions via its Play&Plug technology platform. At Wakam we believe in the formula “for-profit & for good”. Since March 2021, we are a Mission-driven company, which means that our mission statement ‘Enabling transparent and impactful insurance’ is written in our bylaws. And we go further: by defining 9 concrete commitments to illustrate this mission, such as writing our insurance contracts in plain language (no more confusing terms and conditions). We also create insurance products at cost for associations.
​
        Our culture? Free to impact.
​
        A culture where everything is possible, where all ideas are taken into consideration, where everyone has an impact on the transformation of insurance! Hungry for freedom? Thirsty for autonomy? If you are adventurous and like challenges, then the Wakam adventure might be made for you!
​
        To support these products and accelerate our growth, Wakam has built a set of Digital Products and a Data Platform for integrating and storing data from distribution partners (insurance contracts, claims and payments), giving insights to our partners and supporting the various internal data use cases (Business Intelligence, Data Analytics, Data Science and Actuarial).
​
✎ The Mission
Wakam is looking for a Full Stack Developer on a permanent contract, who is committed to technical excellence and enjoys working in an agile context.
​
Reporting to the Data Platform Squad, the Full-Stack Developer participates in the scoping and development of functional and technical evolutions of digital products for our data platform. These digital products are deeply connected with our data platform and will have a large impact on many different users (partners, project managers, data managers, data scientists...).
​
Your main tasks will be to:
​
Participate in the scoping and implementation of new products
Help define the roadmap in conjunction with the Product Manager
Take charge of the development of User Stories (Front & Backend)
Support functional and technical testing phases
Contribute to the platform's robustness, performance, security and UX/UI design
Participate in sprints and team rituals
Participate in forward-looking development work and technology watch, working hand-in-hand with the Architecture team
Support the development team (pairing, code review, share knowledge, etc.)
Ensure that best practices are implemented and respected
​
​
✯ Profile required
You have at least 5 years' successful experience in the development of IT projects and are not afraid to discover new languages:
​
You have strong skills in the following technologies:
​
Python, FastAPI, ReactJS, Typescript, Terraform, Microsoft Azure
​
You are particularly familiar with the following principles:
​
Agile, Clean Code, Hexagonal Architecture, Test Driven Development, REST API, CI/CD
​
You are passionate about topics such as: Software Architecture, Infrastructure as Code, Change Management, Accelerate (Building and Scaling High Performing Technology Organizations)
​
You enjoy sharing your knowledge with your peers and mentoring more junior developers
​
You have previously worked with Data teams is a bonus
​
You have a good command of English in a professional context
​
​
​
Expected qualities:
​
You're passionate about your job and want to share your experience with others
You are constantly seeking to improve through a continuous learning attitude
​
​
Recruitment process
​
Exchange with Danny, Lead Recruiter
Technical and manager interview with our Data Platform Team Lead and a senior member of the Tech teams
Interview with our VP Data
Culture fit exchange with Laura - Head of Talent
​
​
Positive energy, agility, and team spirit are essential to support Wakam in its hyper-growth!
​
You have the Wakam mindset? Join us!
​
More about us
Our culture? Free to impact. A culture where everything is possible, where all ideas are taken into consideration, where everyone has an impact on the transformation of insurance! Hungry for freedom? Thirsty for autonomy? If you are adventurous and like challenges, then the Wakam adventure might be made for you!
​
Discover -on our website- who we really are with the 11 cultural markers that so well describe us!
​
What we are looking for
Mindset compatibility with our ‘Free to Impact’ culture:
​
Think big
Biased for action
Curious and eager to learn
Can say no and find solutions
Aims for the moon (but please don’t stick on the moon)
And above all: have fun working together 🤜🤛 !
Good to know
Wakam is not based on a hierarchy but on a methodology where everyone finds his role and knows his objectives.
With a flat hierarchical system and a highly collaborative operating model, Wakam is an extremely agile and transparent company.
Every last Friday of the month, it's Free.day at Wakam, a day without meetings to take a step aside and dedicate ourselves to skills sponsorship or other activities (because we are curious, I remind you).
Full-remote is a reality at Wakam (there is even one Wakamee who works from his sailing boat ⛵)
Last but not least : we are nice and we have fun! (you'll find out by yourself 😉)
        </description>]]>
        <url>https://boards.eu.greenhouse.io/wakam/jobs/4192882101</url>
        <location>Paris</location>
        <country>France</country>
        <remote>1</remote>
        <company>Wakam</company>
        <category>Engineering Jobs</category>
        <contract_type>permanent</contract_type>
        <contract_time>full_time</contract_time>
    </job>
    <job>
        <title>Full Stack Engineer - Remote from EMEA</title>
        <id>4192882101</id>
        <![CDATA[<description>
​
        </description>]]>
        <url>https://boards.eu.greenhouse.io/wakam/jobs/4192882101</url>
        <location>Paris</location>
        <country>France</country>
        <remote>1</remote>
        <company>Wakam</company>
        <category>Engineering Jobs</category>
        <contract_type>permanent</contract_type>
        <contract_time>full_time</contract_time>
    </job>
    <job>
        <title>Full Stack Engineer - Remote from EMEA</title>
        <id>4192882101</id>
        <![CDATA[<description>
​
        </description>]]>
        <url>https://boards.eu.greenhouse.io/wakam/jobs/4192882101</url>
        <location>Paris</location>
        <country>France</country>
        <remote>1</remote>
        <company>Wakam</company>
        <category>Engineering Jobs</category>
        <contract_type>permanent</contract_type>
        <contract_time>full_time</contract_time>
    </job>
</jobs>
</rss>
